Alexander Stoneham

Student



St Andrews, Scotland Edinburgh, Scotland

me@alexstoneham.co.uk

About

I am highly motivated and hardworking person who strives for excellence in everything I do. I focus on details and always give a task my best. From previous roles I have been equipped with strong teamwork, communication and problem solving skills, as well as the ability to adapt quickly to new challenges. I am now looking to pursue a new role that can further progress me as an individual and improve my skills even more.

Hobbies

During my time at school I played as a snare drummer in the Pipe Band. I was a dedicated member for nearly 10 years and won multiple major championships as well as winning the Pipe Band World Championships in August 2024. I learned the importance of teamwork and communication as well as perseverance when things do not always go your way. Importantly, I was able to perform in a pressuring environment during competitions, and it has allowed me to enhance my focus and resilience.

Aside from music, I'm enthusiastic about computers and programming which influenced my university degree choice. Programming is something I do in my free time as I believe its an important skill to have and is becoming more essential by the day.

Certifications

- First Aid
- PVG

Work experience

Support Worker

Branch Out Together

Feb 2024 - Jun 2024 Edinburgh, Scotland

I spent time during school holidays providing care and support for neurodivergent children between the ages of 5–18. I worked one-to-one with children and learned about their life experiences. I assisted with daily activities, educational tasks, games, and behavioral support to promote learning, independence and emotional well-being. Furthermore, I collaborated with parents and other support workers to implement personalized support. During my time I used de-escalation techniques and sensory strategies to manage challenging behaviours in the children to create a calm and positive atmosphere.

Summer IT Intern

George Watson's College

Jun 2023 - Aug 2023 Edinburgh, Scotland

I was part of a team that installed an array of new technology infrastructure into my school including Macs, PCs, iPads, printers and various pieces of networking equipment, as well as using MDM (mobile device management) software to control hundreds of devices across the whole school network. From this position I learned a great deal in device management systems and enterprise skills that can prove extremely useful in future positions. My role required meticulous attention to detail, technical proficiency and the ability to troubleshoot issues under time constraints in order to keep technical downtime to a minimum.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

University of St Andrews

Sep 2024 - Present St Andrews, Scotland

I am currently in my first year of studies out of four at the University of St. Andrews, studying a degree in Computer Science.

George Watson's College

Nov 2014 - Jun 2024 Edinburgh, Scotland

- 2 A's in Advanced Higher Business and Computer Science
- 5 A's in Higher English, Maths, Accounting, Business, and Computer Science
- 8 A's in National 5 English, Maths, Spanish, Business, Physics, Computer Science, Modern Studies, and Geography

Alexander Stoneham me@alexstoneham.co.uk